In the enormity of the West,
there are still vast and
virtually unexplored regions
bleak and desolate,
where no human ever goes,
and no life is ever seen.
It is as though the land
had been posted by God.
It is in these lonely areas
of impenetrable forest and dark shadows
that the Gila monster still lives.
How large the dreaded Gila
monster grows no man can say.
- Say, here come Gordy and Jennie.
- Hey, gang!
- Hey, where've you been?
- Hi!
- You better cool that foot jazz.
- How's that?
- What about that?
- Well, Spook will be charging you
with an entertainment plan.
- He charges us for everything else.
- Hi, Spook.
- Hi, kids.
Hey, how are
the new parts on the bomb?
- Gordon. Jennie.
Where's Pat and Liz?
I thought we'd be the last ones here.
- Yeah, they're probably out
spooking around somewhere.
- Maybe they broke down.
- Not in his heap.
I worked on myself.
- That makes it too cool.
- That wouldn't make any difference
if they goofed a speed shift or something.
- Yeah, and that squirrel is
just the one that could do it.
- Oh, wonderful.
- What kept you so long, Lisa?
- Oh, Mr. Wheeler smoked two cigars
at the table after dinner,
and I could not get at the
dishes until he was through.
- What time did Pat leave?
- Pat did not come home for dinner.
That's why his father was so upset.
Who's that?
- There's Old Man Harris.
- Man, that fellow has a jewel of a car.
- Well, look then.
- Hey.
- Hi, Mr. Harris.
- Hi, how you doing?
- Hey, you wanna sell that Deuce?
- Why you fellers always
asking me to buy my car?
- That 32 is the ideal
stock to convert to a bomb.
- Buying a car, son,
is just like getting married
or going to New York City.
Everybody ought to do it once,
but nobody ought to do it twice.
- Hey, I can get you a good price on that.
- Paid $695 for that car 26 years ago.
Ten years ago it wasn't worth a dime.
Last month I turned down $100 for it.
When it gets back up to
$695 again, I'll sell it.
Hey, Spook.
Gimme a snort of that there sode pop.
- Hey, gang, you know this will be
Lisa's first trip to a drive-in?
- Oh, we have drive-ins in France, too.
- Yeah?
- Yes.
I went twice with my brother
on his motor scooter.
Oh, her brother
on a motor scooter.
- On a motor scoter!
Now that's my idea of
absolutely nothing to do.
Yeah, okay, come on let's go.
Don't be too late.
- We're gonna pull on out.
- Hey Chase, if the roads clear,
I'll drag you to Bartonelle's Corner.
- I can't, I'm driving barefoot.
You still
running on that old rubber?
- Yeah.
Hey Spook, when Pat and Liz get here,
will you tell them that
we went to the drive-in
and for them to catch up?
Thank you.
- We sure will.
- And I'll give you $150.
- You're talking like my foot's asleep.
Who does he think he's playing with, kids?
- Sheriff.
- What's the trouble, Mr. Wheeler?
- Pat didn't come home last night.
- He didn't?
- No, evidently, he was
out with Liz Humphries.
She didn't come home either.
- Oh?
- I want you to find out why,
and don't leave a stone
unturned in doing so.
Do I make myself clear?
- I understood, Mr. Wheeler.
There weren't any wrecks
reported last night.
Your son Pat he's about 19, isn't he?
- That's right.
- Just a year older than
I was when I got married.
- You think they eloped?
He wouldn't dare.
- I didn't say that.
But if they were out together all night,
you better hope they have.
- This is a missing person's report,
and I wanna know what
you're gonna do about it.
- Well, I'll send in an APB
on both of them and the car.
I don't think it'll do much good
if they went out to get married.
They'd already be across the state line.
- Why, if he'd gotten
married, I'll wring his neck.
If you ask me it's that Chase Winstead.
He's older than the others.
Sets them all wrong.
Why, he's got more influence
on Pat than I have.
- Chase Winstead does more
about keeping them in line
than getting them in trouble than I know.
He supported his mother and sister
ever since his dad died
on one of your drill rigs.
Your son could take a page
out of his book, Mr. Wheeler.
- When I get through with my son,
he won't have a book left.
Now you locate him or I'll have your job.
- If you wanna be the only peace officer
in 10,000 square miles
and 1,000 miles of road,
you're welcome to it.
I'll do everything I can to locate
both of them, Mr. Wheeler.
- Hi, Sheriff.
Hi, Chase.
- Got a new set of wheels.
- Yeah, new to me.
With that clunker I had,
I'd be chasing you boys on a
bicycle in a couple of days.
- Oh, come on, Sheriff.
Outside of Pat Wheeler,
we haven't had a ticket in
our gang in eight months.
- Oh, I was just kidding.
- What's the mileage on it?
- Oh, about 35,000.
County bought it from the state.
Those lucky stiffs on highway
get a new car every year.
- Let me have it for a couple of days,
and I'll tune it up for you.
- Oh, you'd choke it off,
so I could never catch you!
- You couldn't get that
deuce of mine right now!
Now let me have that patrol car.
I'll turn it into a slingshot
that'll catch anything.
- We'll make a deal.
Chase?
Just between us Liz
Humphries and Pat Wheeler
didn't get home last night.
- Oh?
They were supposed to
meet us at the drive-in,
but they didn't show up.
We wondered what happened.
- Were they in any kind of trouble?
- What do you mean?
- You know.
- Oh.
No, I don't think so.
- Chase, level with me.
- I'm almost positive they
weren't in any trouble.
I'd know.
- Do you think they might
have run off to get married?
- Well, they've been going
steady for over a year now,
and I know they talked about it, but...
No, not like for right now.
- Did Pat have any money stashed?
Yeah, some.
- Like how much?
- Well, he was talking about getting
a new blower and a mill.
That's about 500 bucks.
- Where did he get that kind of money?
- He saved it.
His old man gives him a good allowance
when he's not mad at him.
- What bank does he use?
- None.
He's afraid his did would find out.
- He could have been saving it
to get married, couldn't he?
- It's his money.
I guess he could do
whatever he wants with it.
But, you know, if he eloped,
his old man would put him down flat.
- I know.
But Pat's smart enough
to provide for himself
till the old man cooled off.
- Pat's the only one of the
gang I couldn't slow down.
Did you check the hospitals?
- Yeah.
Where could I find the rest of the gang?
- Well, I don't know about Bob and Gordy,
but Chuck and Rick went over to Easton.
They wanted to check with the Wheel Cats
about next Saturday night's platter party.
- Next Saturday night?
- Yeah.
- You warn the gang I'll be
cruising that pass that night.
No dragging.
- Okay, I'll tell them.
- You get any postcards
from those two, let me know.
- Hi, Sheriff.
- Hi, Kelly.
Howdy, Ebb.
- Hello, Sheriff.
- I don't have any word
for you, Mrs. Humphries.
- She's a good girl, Sheriff.
I ain't worried.
- How come you drove around
the truck all night then?
- You don't think she
might have eloped, do you?
- Could be, she's pretty close
mouthed about her affairs.
- More thank likes of Wheeler.
Ain't marrying our kind of folks.
- You don't have a phone,
so I just dropped around
to let you know I'm
doing everything I can.
- We know that, Sheriff,
and we sure do appreciate it.
- Sorry Liz put you to so much trouble.
- It's never any trouble
looking after kids.
- Let me know if I can help, Sheriff.
- Thanks, Ebb.
- Thank you, Sheriff.
- Goodbye.
Yes, we gotta
quit worrying this way.
We gotta trust in the Lord.
We gotta pray.
- Harris.
- Morning, Sheriff.
- Let me smell your breath.
Okay, go ahead.
- Okay.
- Hi, Chase.
- Hi.
- Did you get that diesel tracker fixed?
- Yeah, she's all set.
- Good.
My boy, that's one trip I'm glad
I don't have to make very often.
- The stuff heavy I'll help you unload.
- No, not heavy.
It's hot.
Wheeler's sinking another oil well,
and he's afraid of fire when it comes in.
There's four quarts of nitroglycerin
out there in that cab.
He wants us to keep it out
back in the storehouse.
- You know, last winter
when number 21 came in,
I made a $100 for that stuff.
Dad showed me how to use it.
It's not so bad,
as long as it doesn't get nervous.
- Well, I'm sorry I was late getting back.
But with that cargo,
I was afraid to do over
five miles an hour.
- Oh, it's not so dangerous
as long as it's in a nitro case.
- But I took these out of the case!
- Holy smoke.
You're lucky to be standing
here talking about it!
I'll put it in the shed!
- Much action this afternoon?
- Sheriff got a new patrol car.
We'll get a tune-up job out of that.
- Is that nitro safe out there?
- Well, if it decides to blow,
it's not safe anywhere.
I'll get it.
- That's not our ring.
- No, it's the sheriff's.
If there's been a wreck,
I get a tow job out of it.
I also have a deal with the
ambulance if someone's hurt.
- You work all the
angles, don't you, Chase?
- Mr. Compton, I have to.
Hello, Sheriff?
Yes.
I'm 12 miles out
beyond the red schoolhouse
a car has run into the ditch.
Oh?
Yeah, it's a pretty bad wreck.
What kind of a car?
Well, it's a sedan.
Pontiac, I believe.
Someone could've been hurt pretty bad.
Maybe you should get
out there pretty quick.
Did you stop and investigate?
- There's been a wreck
12 miles out of town.
Where's the wrecker?
- Home.
I used the A-frame to build
a doggone rock garden.
Look, you take your car
and keep the city wreckers off.
I'll get our wrecker and follow you.
- I wondered who was on
that party line a while ago.
- Well, it cost me to get
on that line with you.
I figured since it was on
your call station anyway,
you wouldn't care.
- Yeah.
This is a pretty good one.
Yeah.
This engine's still warm.
- Say, did you see the
skid marks out here?
They go at a direct right angle
to the direction of travel.
- Yeah.
No digs in the macadam either.
Somebody was hurt in here.
There's blood all over the upholstery.
Let's take a look around.
- I've already looked around.
There's nobody here.
- Real good?
- Yeah, real good.
Well, maybe somebody came
by and picked them up.
It could've been the people who called in.
- Nah, they'd have said something.
- Then why didn't they wait?
- People will go to the
trouble to report an accident,
but they won't stay around.
Don't want to fill out the reports.
- So what do you do now?
- Well, I'll take the license
number and engine number.
Call headquarters.
Maybe they've got a line on them.
Chase, how are your headlights?
- Fine, just fine.
- Both of them burning?
How many times have I warned you
about getting that headlamp fixed?
- Twice.
But the first time it
was just a suggestion.
- Seal beam only costs $4.
- Well, I had some unexpected expenses.
- Oh?
Missy?
- Yeah, the doctor said she'd be able
to start walking again pretty soon,
and it took all the money I had
to make a part down payment on her braces.
- You know, I think this
is a complete washout.
You've probably got a screwdriver.
I don't think the insurance company
would miss one of those headlamps.
Well, I got the whole story.
Car was stolen out of state,
and the plates were stolen in state.
So whoever stole it had
beat it, hurt or not,
as long as they could navigate.
- Well, is there anything
else I can do here, Sheriff?
If not, I'll get this
on back to the garage.
- No, go ahead.
Chase, will you give me a hand?
I wanna take some pictures
of those skid marks.
You stand by them for scale.
- Sure, glad to, Sheriff.
- Good.
Trouble, Chase?
- I don't know, Sheriff.
Take a look.
It was just sitting here.
- Probably fell off of a car.
- No scratches on it.
- Yeah, maybe it landed in a bush.
- No, as thin as that
imitation leather is,
even a bush should take some of it off.
- Was it just like that when you found it?
- Yeah, straight up.
- Probably belonged to some hitchhiker,
or it might have belonged to the fella
that stole that car and wrecked it.
Say, look at this.
A half pack of cigarettes and one unlit.
That suitcase don't
belong to any car thief.
He was around here too long.
I'll take it in.
- I'll put it in the car for you.
- Somebody will be around to claim it.
See you later, son.
- Right, Sheriff.
Hey.
What's with the code bit?
I got your phone call.
- When I was serving
dinner to Mr. Wheeler,
he became very angry.
He said if I saw you again,
he would have me sent back to France.
- He can't do that.
- Oh, yes, he can.
He's my sponsor.
He put up the bond.
- That has to guarantee
that you wouldn't become
a ward of the state.
Now, we don't have to worry about that.
You know how to speak English
well enough to get a job anywhere.
- He said it's immoral
for me to go out with you.
What's immoral about it?
- Nothing.
- I don't want to go away, Chase.
- You won't have to, honey.
- They think it's your
fault that Pat ran away.
- Well, he can think
whatever he wants to think.
He shouldn't take it out on you,
but we hadn't better take any chances.
You go back inside,
and, look, don't worry.
Everything's gonna be okay.
You all right?
- All right?
Dad, I'm superb.
Seven to a box, no corners.
I'm around Hal!
- Sorry I asked, Mister, uh?
- Smith.
Horatio Alger Smith.
- Sorry I asked that, too.
How'd you get in the ditch?
You fall asleep?
- Ah, no, no.
There was this big pink
and black thing drove
right in front of me.
It had stripes this wide.
- Sure, sure.
Look, you come up and sit in my truck,
and I'll get your car.
- Okay, that sounds like a good deal.
Who knows, maybe we can...
- Hey, man, you can't drive this car!
Fender's cutting the wheel!
- Sure I can the motor works, see?
But, thanks for everything, Dad.
You're a cotton-picking prince.
- Okay, just a second.
I'll get out of the way.
What is it?
- Move over, Dad, I wanna pass!
- What is it now?
- I think you'd better give me a tow, Dad.
The steering wheel won't work.
Okay, you take a nap.
♪ My baby she rocks and rolls ♪
♪ And rocks whenever she walks ♪
♪ And rocks whenever she talks ♪
♪ My baby's a rock-and-rolling ♪
♪ Tippy toeing, never knowing ♪
♪ Always glowing baby ♪
♪ My baby she swings and sings ♪
♪ And swings whenever I bring her things ♪
♪ She swings and sings ♪
♪ And swings for a little diamond rings ♪
♪ Swinging, singing bells are ringing ♪
♪ Happy playing, pleasure bringing, baby ♪
♪ My baby she rocks and rolls ♪
♪ And rocks whenever she walks ♪
♪ My baby she swings and sings ♪
♪ And swings whenever I bring her things ♪
♪ A rock-and-rolling, tippy toeing ♪
♪ Never knowing, always glowing ♪
♪ Swinging singing, bells are ringing ♪
♪ Happy playing, pleasure bringing baby ♪
Good afternoon, Mr. Smith.
- Like, man, guys have had their heads
chopped off for less than that.
- For what?
- For feeling so doggone
good when I feel so bad.
How'd I get here, anyway?
- I towed you in this morning, remember?
- As a matter of fact, I
remember very, very little.
- You said somebody
ran you into the ditch,
but I didn't see any other cars.
- How'd you ever get
me in that bed, anyway?
- I carried you in there,
and I sat on you till you fell asleep.
- That must've been quite a chore.
- You wouldn't have gotten
very far in your condition.
- Look, I really appreciate it, um?
- Chase Winstead.
- Chase.
My golly, how much I owe you?
- Well, I bent the fender
out from the wheel.
You want me to fill it in
and touch it up for you?
- No, I don't think so.
I'll get that done when
I get back to the city.
- Here have some coffee.
- Oh, great.
- How about two bucks?
- Man, this coffee's worth
two bucks all by itself.
How about the tow?
- No, I was coming this way anyway.
I missed out on a little study time.
Make it three bucks?
- Dad, you go to school?
- Sort of, I take a correspondence
course in engineering.
- Well, look, I really
feel indebted to you,
and I'd like to do
something to pay you back.
No next time you're into
town, there's my card.
Look me up, will you?
- All right, will do.
- Okay.
And by the way,
buy yourself a sponge rubber hammer, man.
- All right, I will.
- I'll see you, Chase.
- Thank you.
Steamroller Smith?
The disk jockey.
Mr. Smith!
Two 20s!
How about that.
Sheriff?
- Howdy, son.
Have you heard anything from Pat and Liz?
- No, nothing.
- Chase, I'm in a jam,
and I need your help.
Wheeler swings a big enough stick
in this country to make it rough,
and he's doing it.
Oh, I can understand
his concern about Pat,
but I just don't have a big enough force
to comb this area inch-by-inch.
- Is he demanding that?
There was a man killed in a wreck
in a small canyon in a big city last year,
and it took them 19 days to find him.
I don't know what they expect of me.
- Yeah, I remember that.
Look Sheriff, maybe I
can get tomorrow off,
and I'll get the gang,
and we can go out and search that pass.
At least you can put that in your report.
- I was hoping you'd say that.
I can start at the upper
end and work towards you.
Can I have your help in another matter?
- Sure. What?
- You remember how those
skid marks just went at
right angles to the direction
the car was traveling?
- That's right, they did.
- Headquarters think I'm nuts.
- Well then, they're nuts.
Didn't you send them that picture?
- Well, I'm not the world's
greatest photographer.
Pictures didn't come out.
Can't see the skid marks on the black top.
- Well, that's what happened.
I even wiped up the rubber
dust with my fingers.
- You might have to sign a
statement to that effect for me.
- You've got it.
Look, you can even see the
bald spots on the tires
where they went sideways...
- Yeah, that's the spot all right.
But there's another thing that puzzles me.
- Yeah, what?
- How those tires got off of
that car and almost on yours.
- Well, look on this wreck, they'd rot,
and my rod they could prevent a blowout.
Maybe even an accident.
- Well, take good care of them
in case the owner shows up.
- Right.
- See you tomorrow.
- Let's call it a day.
We've covered half the
roads in this county.
- Yeah.
How about that ravine?
That runs along here
for about eight miles.
We'll start from here,
and you come from the other end.
- Well, all right.
- Right.
Sure is beat down around here.
Look at that!
- What is it, Chase?
- Looks like an animal of some sort
drug something along here.
- You mean a wild animal here?
- Sure, could be anything,
even a mountain lion.
Come on.
Thirsty?
- Yes, but haven't we
gone far enough, Chase?
- Phew that's bitter.
Must have an awful lot of mineral in it.
- Come on, let's go.
- Wait a minute.
Let's take a breather first.
- Chase, I don't like this place.
Let's go back.
- Are you afraid?
Now you come on over here
with me and sit in the shade,
and I'll you a story.
That's Gordy maybe
they've found something!
Come on, let's go!
- It's Pat's car at
the bottom of the wash,
two or three miles back
by the old reservoir.
- Were they in it?
- No, nothing.
- Drive me back to my car,
and I'll bring up the wrecker.
- I wonder what that was.
- Oh, probably just a little rock slide.
- For some reason this
place gives me the creeps.
It always has.
- Lisa.
Turn the motor on.
The wench is already engaged.
Now, if I yell, turn the key off.
Okay.
- Okay?
Go ahead.
Give it some more.
Okay, keep going.
Keep going.
Attagirl.
Keep it going.
Keep it going you're doing fine.
Attagirl.
Attagirl, keep it going.
You doing fine.
You did fine, honey.
- It's a little beat up,
but it'll tow all right.
- Yeah, we'll meet you
back at the garage, okay?
- Let's go, Jenny.
- See you later.
Where did you find it?
- By the reservoir in Williams Wash.
They weren't in it.
There's no sign of blood or anything.
You know, I think they were thrown clear.
- Did you search the area?
- Yeah, Gordy went down the
ravine for about a mile,
and, well, we looked beyond the wreck
for a couple hundred yards.
Wouldn't you say, Gordy?
- At least that far.
- Did you see any footprints?
- No, none.
- This thing's bent around
just about the same as that sedan,
like it'd been hit with
a 10-ton rubber mount.
- It's a pretty rough
trip down that cliff.
That could have done it.
- Yeah, I'll have to go
over that area with a rake.
- You know, I've been thinking.
If Liz and Pat had eloped,
they wouldn't have take his car
because Old Man Wheeler would
have it traced right off.
- Well, maybe he stole it, Chase,
and then it was stolen.
- Yeah, if it was stolen and
somebody parked it there,
well, the brakes could have faded,
and it rolled off the edge.
- It'd be a strange coincidence
if they came back to
this part of the county.
The possibility makes some sense, though.
I'll get my gear and
dust for fingerprints.
Gosh, I wish you boys had have called me
before you drug it out.
I might have found some
clues to help us out.
- I'm sorry, Sheriff.
- The hard part's telling Mr. Wheeler.
I sure dread that.
- It's not like we found them there.
- He's sure gonna raise Ned
because I don't find this wreck sooner.
Where's Mr. Compton?
- He went down to the field
with a load of fuel oil.
He'll be back in two or three hours.
I'm gonna close up.
- I'll see you later.
- Sorry I'm late.
- Now, Chase Winstead.
Just a minute jot so fast there.
- What for?
Did you ever play football?
- With the Green Bay Packers.
- Hike!
- Oh, Chase, put me down.
- No, not till you tell
me what's going on.
- All right, if you close your eyes.
- All right, I don't
know what's happening,
but they're closed.
- Keep them closed.
- They're closed.
This is silly.
- Now, open them.
- Look what Lisa got me.
Stay there, Chase.
Watch.
I can get up.
Stay there.
That was wonderful, baby.
Just wonderful.
- But I've been practicing all afternoon,
ever since Lisa brought the braces over,
and I walked all the way, twice.
I wanted to do it right for you.
- Would you like to hear a song?
♪ There was a mushroom ♪
♪ Sad little mushroom ♪
♪ And there was a meadow ♪
♪ Ready to cry ♪
♪ There was a sparrow ♪
♪ Gray little sparrow ♪
♪ And there was an eagle ♪
♪ Silent and high ♪
♪ And the Lord said ♪
♪ Laugh, children laugh ♪
♪ The Lord said laugh, children, laugh ♪
♪ The Lord said, laugh, children, laugh ♪
♪ The Lord said laugh, laugh, laugh ♪
♪ Then the Lord he said
I created for you ♪
♪ A world from out of the blue ♪
♪ And all that is left
to complete the joy ♪
♪ Just the laugh of a girl and boy ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ And there was a garden ♪
♪ Beautiful garden ♪
♪ Held in the arms of
a world without joy ♪
♪ Then there was laughter ♪
♪ Wonderful laughter ♪
♪ For he created a girl and a boy ♪
♪ And the Lord said,
laugh, children, laugh ♪
♪ The Lord said, laugh, children, laugh ♪
♪ The Lord said laugh, children, laugh ♪
♪ The Lord laugh ♪
♪ Yay ♪
- Laughing's important, isn't it, Chase?
- It sure is,
and, you know, I never
felt any more like laughing
than I do right now.
I didn't think you'd be able
to do that good in a week.
- Didn't you really?
- Honest.
But, you know, you're gonna
have to work real hard,
and you mustn't be disappointed
if it takes a long time, okay?
- That's enough for one day, Missy.
It's your bedtime.
- Do I have to, Chase?
- You sure do.
Show me how you can walk.
- Goodnight, Lisa.
- That was a wonderful
thing for you to do, Lisa.
- I wanted to.
- Now you're broke, aren't you?
I was gonna pick them up in the morning.
- I know.
When you showed me that money
I was afraid you'd get there first.
- Well, I'm still gonna pay you for them.
- No.
- Yes.
Yes.
Hello?
Yeah, Sheriff.
Well, he should have
been back an hour ago.
No.
Where?
That's awful.
No, it couldn't be Mr. Compton.
All right.
At the garage?
All right, I'm leaving now.
- What is it, Chase?
- It's a wreck, and oil truck.
It could be Mr. Compton.
Honey, I'm awfully sorry,
but I've got to leave.
- Here he comes now, Sheriff.
- Come on.
- Wait a minute, Sheriff.
You've got a sore foot.
- Oh, no.
- We can take my Model A.
She's all shiny and bright brand new.
- No, we'll take my car.
- Come on, Harris.
- Did you see it?
- No, I didn't see it,
but I sure heard about it.
- Can I open this thing up?
- Yeah, go ahead.
That's Compton's rig!
Be careful, it's pretty hot.
- He's not in it.
- He may have been hurt and crawled away.
Let's look around.
Come on, Harris!
- Okay.
- Compton!
Mr. Compton!
- Find anything, Sheriff?
- Well, let's go over this again.
How did you get into the act?
- I told you once.
- Well, tell me again.
- Well, I was barrelling
along in my Model A.
She don't look like much now,
but she was a beauty when I first--
- The accident.
- Still go though.
Get up to 60.
- The accident.
Just the accident.
- Well, I'll tell you.
- I wish you would.
- This feller seen the headlights
coming up the grade towards him,
and all of a sudden they come
at you going over and over,
and then blewy.
Blewy, she blew up!
Well, he seen somebody
is in a might of trouble,
so he come in the store talking about it.
That's when I offered to call you.
- Did you get the name of the witness?
- No.
- Did he see anything else?
- Nope.
- Do you wanna wait in the car for us?
- No.
- Well, you're going to anyway.
- Okay, Sheriff.
Okay.
Like you say, always obey the law.
Do this, do that.
Somebody tells you no...
- Any luck, Chase?
- No, nothing.
- Pat and Liz might have eloped,
but Compton ought to be around here.
- Maybe he's in the hospital.
- No, I checked there
before I left my place.
Would Compton have any
reason to want to get lost?
- No, none that I can think of.
- You would have no
reason to know about this,
but there's been a lot of
livestock missing lately.
One here, one there.
That doesn't make headlines,
but now it's people.
- Do you think there's a tie-up?
- I don't know.
What we need is a criminal investigator,
and headquarters won't send one down here.
- Well, maybe they will now.
- Yeah, maybe.
Did you notice those skid marks?
Just like the others,
straight across the road.
If it'd been hit by another vehicle,
the paint would be knocked off.
What batters a car
around like it was a toy?
- How's the barn coming
along for the party?
- All right, I'll be done
in about an hour or so.
Say, you and Chase sure got off light.
He took off this morning.
You've just sitting around
here on your can all day long.
That barn was a place to clean.
- You get the hi-fi set up?
- Yeah.
Well, you
steamboats and dreamboats.
That's
Steamroller Smith.
He's the most.
Steamroller here at KILT.
Now if any of you round rocks
get lonesome for my voice,
I'll be MC'ing a platter party tonight
out at Hargitay's Barn on Route 43.
Drop in, I'll flatten you.
- Hey, man, that's us.
We got the steamroller coming out.
- That's where Chase has been all day.
Getting steamroller!
- This will be a blast.
- How about that guy?
Say little man, you sure had a busy day.
- Getting that paint job
and Steamroller Smith.
- Now how'd you guys find
out about Steamroller Smith?
- Well, he just said so on his program.
Said it right out on the network.
- Well, I wanted it to be a surprise.
Well come on, don't spread around, huh?
How are the preparations coming?
- Oh, that'll be finished
about 45 minutes.
The gang won't start arriving
from east until 9:30.
- We're under the wire with time to spare.
- No sweat.
♪ Oh, I hate the ground you
walk on, little darling ♪
♪ For all them things
that you have did to me ♪
♪ Oh, you nagged me till you're hoarse ♪
♪ So I'm suing for divorce ♪
♪ Little darling I'll forget your memory ♪
It's good.
Come on, Tessie Belle.
Let's go.
- That's the same story
a man down here told me.
Something real strange must
have happened down there.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
He'll be here if you want him.
Right.
Sit down, Harris.
- You be going down to the wreck, Sheriff?
- No, that's not in my territory.
Headquarters already have a report.
The troopers will take care of that.
Harris, tell me again
about the train wreck.
- Well, I was driving around
quiet like in my Model A.
Bought it in '32 for--
- Just a minute.
Just a minute.
I ask you what time it is,
and you tell me how to build a clock.
Just the facts about the wreck.
- Well,
I was driving along quiet like.
- The wreck.
- Then I turned around
and come back down here
and told you about it.
- Give me your keys, Harris.
- Keys?
My keys.
What for?
- For spinning a yarn like
that and driving while drunk.
- I demand a soberty test.
- That does it.
Go lock yourself up.
- I demand a soberty test,
because I ain't been drinking.
Well, a least not as heavy.
Whatever you think's right.
Which way is the cell?
Which way?
Well, you can't win them
all, can you, Sheriff?
- Call your wife if you want to, Harris.
- What?
Are you crazy, Sheriff?
♪ My baby she rocks and rolls ♪
♪ And rocks whenever she talks ♪
- Chase.
- Hey, you gonna leave home?
- I'm going to spend the
night with the Blackwells.
Mommy said it was all right.
Will you take me over?
- Well, I don't know, Missy.
Gosh, that's two or
three miles outta my way.
Aw, sure, we will.
- Chase.
What in the world have you
done to that car of yours?
- It's a new fuel mixture you like it?
- I just barely touched the gas pedal,
and the back wheel started to spin.
Why, I was two blocks down the road
before I even knew I'd left home.
- Come on, Mom, I'm just trying to make
a hot rodder out of you.
I'll get it.
Hello?
Yeah, hello, Sheriff.
A what?
Book on reptiles?
Yeah, I guess I still have
it around here somewhere.
Yeah, sure.
I have to take Missy
over by the Blackwells.
I'll stop by on my way
to pick up Lisa, okay?
- Well, now I'm gonna tell
you something you don't know.
I've been talking to a zoologist,
and the Gila monster size is controlled,
like everything else,
by a sort of thyroid or pituitary gland.
Sometimes a change in diet can throw
the balance all outta whack.
Either the cells breakdown
too fast or build up too slow,
and this subset makes either
runts or giants out of them.
- Good, but what's that mean to me?
- Well, I'm coming to that.
The zoologist also told me about a doctor
that just found the bones
of some huge animals down in Tanganyika,
and the theory was that they
lived in river delta country,
and certain salts that
had washed into the valley
had been absorbed by the plants
and then transferred to the animals.
causing them to be giants.
- Hmm.
All right.
- Yeah, I know.
I probably sound a little bit like Harris,
but let me tell the whole
thing in my own words.
There was another report out
of Russia or the Ukraine.
It was in the paper a couple months ago,
maybe you saw it,
about a baby that weighed 130 pounds
when it was 10 months old and
was taller than its mother?
Grew up to be a giant.
- Yeah, and that same thing
could happen right here.
Did you see any footprints
around any of those wrecks?
- No.
Gila monster footprints?
- Yeah, a big one,
about the size of a bus.
- Oh, come on.
Are you serious?
- Well, I don't know.
But Harris saw it,
and some of the survivors
of the train wreck saw it.
A giant lizard.
- Train wreck where?
At the bridge
over Wilson's Wash.
- When?
- Tonight, about an hour ago.
The troopers were inclined to pass it off
as shock or optical illusion.
You can't always believe what Harris says.
- A Gila monster, pink and black stripes.
You know, I towed a guy in the other day
and he said he'd been forced off the road
by something like that.
I didn't believe him,
because he'd been drinking,
and another thing when we
were looking for Pat's car,
we saw where something had
been drug down the wash.
You know, if they could
have gotten that big,
they could have knocked Mr.
Compton's truck off that road.
They could've gotten him.
- I shouldn't have told you about this
until after the party.
But I just thought you'd want to know.
- Hadn't we better warn everybody?
- No.
It operates in and around the Wash.
Troopers have got that staked
off for a couple of miles.
Just keep it to yourself.
It might cause panic.
- Okay, Sheriff, whatever you say.
- Try and forgot it for now,
and have some fun, will you, boy?
- Yeah.
All right, hold it!
Hold it, all you jumping beans!
Now, I've got a surprise for you.
We got the king of the DJs.
Now, you've all heard him
on his platter show on KILT.
That's right!
Steamroller Smith!
- Hi.
Okay, your Old Dad here
has some small words
and some great records.
I want you to have a ball tonight.
Let's begin with one of
the top KILT survey songs.
What do you say now let's everybody dance.
Here we go.
Let's go, everybody.
- Yeah.
Now do you mind telling
me what this is all about?
- Have you been down to the train wreck?
- No.
- Well, I have.
I talked to a trooper about my son's car.
He said it shouldn't have been moved
until a thorough
investigation had been made,
and it had been photographed.
This wasn't done, was it, Sheriff?
I thought not.
It was removed and clues
lost without authority.
You didn't put that in your
report, did you, Sheriff?
Of course you didn't,
and I'll tell you why.
You were protecting that Chase Winstead,
covering him regardless of the effect
it might have on others.
- Chase was only trying to help.
He's your son's friend,
probably the best one he ever had.
Of course, it wasn't in the report.
What good would it do?
Any kid can make a mistake,
Mr. Wheeler, even yours.
- But Sheriff, it's my son that's missing.
Let me ask you something else.
Have you heard the reports
about a giant lizard?
You believe them?
- I don't know, Mr. Wheeler.
It doesn't seem possible.
- Well, why not, there
have been giants before.
- That's true.
But how could anything that
big go unnoticed in this area?
- Have you ever walked the
length of William's Wash?
- No.
- Do you know anybody that has?
- That area is so choked with underbrush,
it isn't even good hunting ground,
and I say it is possible
for a giant lizard
to have lived there for
years without being seen.
Now,
if that is the case,
my son's dead.
So is Compton.
I can't blame you for
what's happened to Pat,
but Compton's death is on your hands.
- How did you come to that conclusion?
- I'll tell you how.
His truck was found only
two miles beyond Pat's car,
and if you'd have investigated
that area thoroughly
as you're paid to do,
Compton might not have died.
Well?
Now come out here I wanna
show you something else.
Now something may have hit this car.
But it didn't take the tires off,
and where did those new white sidewalls
on Chase Winstead's hot rod come from?
- Here, I guess.
There was a towing charge against--
He presumed the bill wouldn't be paid,
so he borrowed the tires in the meantime?
- Perhaps.
- That's thievery!
Destroying evidence and
obstructing justice!
Now, your last official act of office
will be to arrest that
boy and bring him in,
and I'll go along to
make sure that it's done.
- Hey, kids, a fellow dropped
in over at KILT the other day
and played me a great new song.
I thought it was just fine.
I wanna play it for you.
We got a little pickup group together
and cut a demo of this guy.
I wanna play it for you now
and see what you think about it.
By the way, the first person
who identifies the singer on the record
gets two free rides on my
elephant in Bangkok, Siam.
But you gotta pay your own
way over there and back.
Okay, here it is now.
See what you think of it.
♪ Cause, baby, I ain't made that way ♪
♪ No, baby, I ain't made that way ♪
♪ But if your madden heart desires ♪
♪ Well, I can give you golden fire ♪
♪ Yes, I can give you golden fire ♪
- Don't give up tar and feathers yet.
I'm gonna play the rest of it.
How do you like it?
Okay, who's the singer?
- Elvis.
One of the Everleys.
- Bill Darnell.
- Kate Smith.
- Very funny, but you lose.
Look, the same guy you
hear singing on the record
also wrote the song.
Now who is it?
Does anybody know?
- We don't know who is it?
- Okay, okay.
It's going to come out on
records in a couple of months,
and you can find his name on the label.
- I know who it is.
Who?
- Who is it, Lisa?
Come on tell us.
Chase did it!
- You did it, Chase?
- Why didn't you say something?
- You didn't tell us.
- Well, I didn't know
if there was anything
I'd want to admit to.
- Come on up here, boy.
All right.
Okay, hold it, hold it.
Quiet, everybody.
Also, up at the station the other day
Chase played me another little song.
It's kind of different from this one,
but I imagine with a little coaxing,
you know, by hitting your
hands together like this,
he might give you a little preview of it.
What do you say?
♪ And the Lord said
laugh, children, laugh ♪
♪ The Lord said laugh, children, laugh ♪
♪ The Lord say laugh, children, laugh ♪
♪ And the Lord said
laugh, children, laugh ♪
♪ The Lord said laugh, children, laugh ♪
♪ The Lord said laugh, laugh, laugh ♪
♪ And the Lord said
laugh, children, laugh ♪
♪ The Lord said ♪
- Just a minute.
♪ The Lord said laugh, children, laugh ♪
♪ The Lord said laugh, laugh, laugh ♪
♪ And then the Lord, he
said, I created for you ♪
♪ A world of joy from out of the blue ♪
Go and help Penny!
What'll it take to stop that thing?
- I don't know, but I'm
going down to the train wreck
and get some troopers.
If we pump enough lead into that thing,
we may hit a vulnerable spot.
Wheeler, you're gonna
have to give me a hand.
- But how?
- Keep these kids here.
I don't want anybody roaming around.
- Where are we going?
- Storage shed.
I've got an idea that might work.
- You been after this.
Now you've got it.
You're deputized.
Listen, kids.
Wheeler's my deputy?
You'll take your orders from him.
Arrest anybody that tries to get away.
- Sheriff says this is the place to stay.
But we're not staying here.
- That's right.
- I'll have to arrest anyone that leaves.
- Now you take these keys
and wait inside the
office till I get back.
I told you to wait inside.
Why don't you do what I tell you?
I haven't got much time.
- You're not going to leave me, Chase.
I'm going to help.
- Do you know what's in here?
Nitroglycerin.
Enough to blow up half this town.
- It doesn't matter.
I'm still going to help.
- Holy.
All right, now take these, hold them,
and don't let them bump,
and for heaven sakes don't drop them.
Now hold those.
Boy, he went through here, all right.
Now, they generally
travel in a straight line.
Good Lord, he's hit the Blackwell home!
That's where Missy is!
Mrs. Blackwell?
Missy?
Mrs. Blackwell!
Missy!
Hang on to that nitro
we're cutting across!
Keep that stuff still.
Do you want to blow us up?
There they are.
Where is Missy?
- Missy!
It's all right, Missy!
It's all right!
Lisa, get Missy and hold her down,
and both of you lie flat!
Are you all right?
- I was scared, Chase.
- That's okay, honey.
- I tore my new dress.
- Oh, we can get you a new dress.
- A hundred dresses.
- Everybody all right?
- Yeah.
- On the way back we picked up his trail,
followed him across country.
What did you hit him with?
- My brand new, 100% completed hot rod.
- You'd have to start the next county
to get up enough momentum
to do that to him.
- Not with four quarts of
nitroglycerin riding with you.
- You rode across that
rough field carrying nitro?
- Yes, sir!
- Do you know what could
have happened to you?
- It did.
I lost my car.
- Oh, don't worry about that.
Railroad will be glad
to buy you a new one.
- Did you see me run,
Chase, did you see it?
- I sure did, Missy.
You were really travelling.
- I thought I told you to keep
those kids up at the barn?
- Well, how do you arrest a bunch of kids
going in all different directions?
- Do you realize what would have happened
if that thing had turned back?
- Same thing that happened to Pat.
Sheriff, your job is a much
bigger one than I thought.
Since Compton's gone,
I guess Chase is out of a job.
- That's right.
- Would you make it a point
to have the boy come around
and see me in the morning?
- I'll bring him around in the morning.